gnu parallel dude I've been I've been
telling you to use gnu parallel for how
long now I swear I I just sit here and I
look at this and it just makes me want
to die a little bit on the inside how
many times do I have to tell you
just learn your command line tools okay
gnu parallel is out of this world good
now here's the deal if you just take a
moment uh
if you just take just a small moment and
learn to write all your programs like
this all your CLI tools like this is
that your CLI tool should operate in one
of a couple ways first off you should be
able to take your standard in right as
input you should also be able to take in
just any old file as an input right you
get a file path as an input your output
should either be the standard out
right
or you should be able to specify as a
command line property a file to go to
all right and then lastly all output you
want to see but you don't want to
interrupt basic program flow you should
just put two standard error right this
is just like how you should do this the
reason why this is so good is when you
have a program like parallel let's just
say that you need to go and you can make
unlimited connections it's not about the
connections it's just simply about
getting
you know the the goodness is in right
you just need to be able to do this so
what you could do is you could have a
process that goes and gets data right
you get a bunch of data you get data and
then after that you can take that and
you can just pipe this in to parallel
and just pass in the script you want to
run and so that every single row of that
data coming back it goes and does that
thing and then you can say like hey I
want to constrain parallel to only 25
running parallel processes you can like
constrain it you can do a bunch of stuff
as long as you follow this little thing
right here you will never run into
problems with running things super fast
on your own system and like it's so
important just just learn the thing just
learn just just just learn the thing and
then here's a little last little tip I
do you see this little call right here
let's pretend this is an asynchronous uh
call it kind of sucks it is what it is
and so you have to do it so what I
typically do let's just call it GD is
I'll do a get data and I'll pipe it into
t
and then I'll put a little break point
in here right out right and then I'll do
the next pipe into like parallel
and do the next little thing and so that
way what I can do is I can have like a
little break point so I don't have to
refetch the data and if I have several
stages in my pipe I'll throw a little T
in there so I can get the data at these
little various points you know I mean
because like at one point I had to fetch
like
three or four different pieces of data
from three or four different databases
and there was like hundreds of thousands
of lines I had to go through for
Netflix's gaming stuff and so it's like
I just had to like I kept teeing along
the way because as I got some of the
data I could save that break point and
so just in case like my internet died
which it does the VPN shits the bed
which it does all the time my goodness
what's t t literally takes standard in
saves it to the file and prints it back
out on standard out so it's like a break
point right on uh on your on your piping
it's very very good
it's very very good there you go right
better
you know tools honestly just just start
here you've got to start here this is
like my most valuable lesson for the
last couple years is just like focus
more on reading standard in and writing
to standard out and using standard error
more appropriately and then also having
this little file escapes the reason why
I really like file escapes is that let's
just say that you want to write say an
integration test or an end-to-end test
for your little command line Library if
you have file and standard in as the
same thing and they can both be read the
same way you can use the file operator
you can use a file as like your uh test
input and so that way you have a golden
input you can have a golden output and
then you can just compare the two files
you can literally run the file you know
run your program with this file out to
this file compare the results and it
makes it super super simple to write
stuff and so I just do that all the time
like that is my way of trying to write
things is always doing that yes I call
it the golden shower test it's my
favorite kind of test I do actually want
to do a front and Master's course on
writing good tools I think that'd be
actually a lot of fun to do and it's
kind of like right up my Alleyway the
golden what it's the Golden Test pick
what did you think I said what what the
name is I can't believe this became a
YouTube video